bloomfire.com 2014-08-02

# Bloomfire

Home > Privacy Policy

## Introduction

This is the Privacy Policy of the Bloomfire website (the "Site"), operated by Bloomfire, Inc. (together with our affiliates and subsidiaries, "Bloomfire", "we", "us", "our", and terms of similar meaning) and our related products and services. It describes the information that we collect from you as part of the normal operation of our Site, and how we use and disclose this information.

By accepting the Privacy Policy in registration or by visiting and using the Site, you expressly consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to our Terms of Use.

In this Privacy Policy, we use the following terms to describe different types of visitors to our Site. Our customers and owners of Bloomfire portals are called "Subscribers." Subscribers may invite other people to use their Bloomfire portal which we will refer to as "Users." Subscribers may upgrade Users to "Administrators" or "Admin" which would allow access to reporting and analytics information. People who visit our website shall be referred to as "Visitors."

## What information we collect

From Visitors we collect the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, aggregate information on what pages Visitors access or visit, and information volunteered by the Visitor.

From Users and Administrators we collect information such as name and email. It is optional that Users and Administrators provide job role, bio information, and profile picture—this information will be collected if provided.

From Subscribers we collect all information as for Users and Administrators. In addition we collect billing address, credit card information, and phone number.

## How we use your information

We store and use personal information for many purposes. The information we collect is used to improve the content of our Site and the quality of our service, and is not shared with or sold to other organizations for commercial purposes, except to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your permission or it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Terms of Use, or as otherwise required by law.

We may use your email address or other personal information to send occasional commercial, educational, or marketing messages. Bloomfire is compliant with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. However, if you wish to opt-out of these emails you can easily unsubscribe with the 'unsubscribe' or 'opt-out' links contained within them or with an email to [communications@bloomfire.com](mailto:communications@bloomfire.com) (1). We may use your email address without further consent for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major system updates, customer service needs, or items for which you have requested communication).

We use cookies, web beacons, and log file information to: (a) store information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit Bloomfire; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, sweepstakes, and contests.

We reserve the right to share your information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law. In exceptionally rare circumstances where national, state or company security is at issue (such as with the World Trade Center terrorist act in September, 2001), we reserve the right to share our entire database of visitors and customers with appropriate governmental authorities.

## How we store and protect information

Bloomfire uses third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run Bloomfire. Although Bloomfire owns the code, databases, and all rights to the application and feedback, you retain all rights to your data.

Bloomfire strives to protect your personal information. For security of transactions, we use the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts any information, such as credit card number and billing information, you send to us electronically. The encryption process protects your information, by scrambling it before it is sent to us from your computer. Once Bloomfire receives your transmission, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our system. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. More information about security is available on the Site and in our Terms of Use.

## Transfer of customer information

Customer lists and information are properly considered assets of a business. Accordingly, if we merge with another entity or if we sell our assets to another entity, our customer lists and information, including personally identifiable information you have provided us, would be included among the assets that would be transferred.

## Other information

Bloomfire adheres to the US Safe Harbor privacy principles. For more information about the Safe Harbor framework, see the Department of Commerce's website at <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>.

For disputes regarding our collection or use of your information or for more information or questions regarding the Privacy Policy, including limitations on damages and the application of the laws of the State of Texas, please see our Terms of Use or please contact us by email at [support@bloomfire.com](mailto:support@bloomfire.com) or by mail at:

Bloomfire, Inc.  
1717 W. 6th Street, Suite 100  
Austin, Texas 78703  
USA

The above contact information may also be used to request access to the information we collect about you. This access may be subject to a fee to cover our costs.

As a convenience to our Visitors and Users, the Site may contain links to a number of sites that we believe may offer useful information. The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to those sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy, security, data collection, and distribution policies.

(1) E-mails from [communications@bloomfire.com](mailto:communications@bloomfire.com) (or any other internal @bloomfire address are represented in the statement above. If you become a member of an independent trial or owned Bloomfire community, you have direct control of those messages within your Bloomfire profile page. See more information here <https://community.bloomfire.com/posts/524060> on how to control those notification settings.
